DUMAGA OKEKE

Senior Software Developer

okekedumaga10@gmail.com https://dumaga-okeke.netlify.app/ 6399946001 Edmonton, AB, T5T5X9, Canada

I am passionate about building excellent websites that improves lives. I specialize in JavaScript/.NET and other frameworks, with knowledge and experience in a variety of other programming languages, I have a keen eye for design, web security and bug fixes.

Core Skills

JAVASCRIPT, PHP, Typescript, Git, Visual Studio Code, Amazon EC2, Github, HTML5, CSS3, DevOps, API, Entra, .NET, AWS, AWS Cloud, Linux, Bash, Python, Terraform, Microservices

Education

Saskatchewan Polytechnic

Aug 2023 - Jun 2024

Certificate Cyber Security Post-Graduate

Tansian University

Jan 2015 - Dec 2019

Bachelor of Computer Science

Languages

English (fluent)

Certificates

Certified Cloud Practitioner

AWS

ISC2 Cyber Security

ISC2

Work Experience

Front-End Developer (Contract)

AIS Web Technologies | Martensville, SK

Sep 2023 - Aug 2024

- Collaborated with cross-functional teams to ensure Business
 Requirements are met and reflected accurately in the final product
- Led a team to design and build robust software solutions for numerous clients, significantly boosting company revenue
- Maintained high uptime for critical software applications, ensuring optimal performance and minimal disruptions
- Leveraged innovative coding techniques to optimize software functionality and increase overall system efficiency.
- Demonstrated advanced problem solving skills through the successful identification and rectification of critical bugs in legacy systems

Full Stack Developer (Remote)

Jan 2023 - May 2024

The Branding Champs LLC | Boulder, Colorado

- Managed and improved application configuration processes to enhance software performance as a Senior Software Developer
- Reviewed existing website features for potential updates, helping to ensure compliance with the latest industry best practices
- Implemented DevOps practices to streamline software development and deployment processes
- Leveraged skill in Developing Cloud platforms and setting up virtual environments, optimizing operational speed and scalability
- Conducted regular Code Reviews to ensure software quality, efficiency and adherence to best coding practices

Desktop Support Lead

Jun 2021 - Jan 2023

Treasures Suites & Conferences | Abuja, Nigeria

- Implemented efficient Customer Data Management processes, which led to improved customer service
- Utilized Continuous Improvement methodologies in software development projects that resulted in successful on-time delivery
- Implemented software solutions while keeping in mind the principles of Network Administration to maintain system security
- Designing and implementing graphic designs used on display screens, and menus.
- Boosted team performance through providing feedback and guidance on front end development projects, resulting in more efficient workflows and higher quality outputs

IT Support Technician

Dec 2019 - Dec 2020

Eta Zuma Mining and Industries Ltd | Abuja, Nigeria

 Utilized strong understanding of Information Systems to design and implement functional WordPress sites

- Utilized supervisory skills to mentor team members on new technologies and best practices for front end development
- Demonstrated independent Solve Complex Problems in troubleshooting and resolving complex front end design issues

• Documentation for future reference among the IT team.

Junior Full stack developer

Mar 2018 - Sep 2019

Nigeria Communication Satellite Limited | Abuja, Nigeria

- Used Unit Testing methodologies to streamline debugging process and accelerate Development Life Cycle
- Used Data Integration strategies to streamline data from various sources for improved user interface design and functionality
- Developed comprehensive User Documentation for multiple software products, enhancing user understanding and experience
- Leveraged human relations skills to resolve conflicts within the team, ensuring smooth workflow and timely project delivery
- Adapted to work schedule to accommodate team needs and project timelines in software development